providentcu.org 2010-12-23

# Privacy Policy

## Privacy Notice

Print

### We take safeguarding your information seriously.

Provident Credit Union and its affiliate, Provident Services Corporation, (PSC), are committed to providing you with financial products and services to meet your financial objectives at every stage of your life. We understand the importance of safeguarding your member information. You can count on us to provide you with the responsive, professional service you deserve. Plus, you can trust Provident to protect your privacy and security at all times. 

This Privacy Policy describes how Provident and PSC collect and use your personal and financial information, and how we maintain the confidentiality and accuracy of such information. This policy is provided pursuant to Title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (the Federal Privacy Act) and the Fair Credit Reporting Act Affiliate Marketing rule.

If you have questions after reading this notice, please contact us at (650) 508-0300 or (800) 632-4600.

### Important highlights of our commitment to our members.

  * We do not sell member information with outside parties or to third parties.
  * We are committed to protecting your member information in every transaction, at every level of our organization.
  * We are committed to helping you protect your privacy every day.
  * What follows is more information about our Privacy Policy, and what we do to protect your member information at Provident Credit Union.

### Information We Collect About You

We collect and maintain your non-public personal information to serve you and to administer your business relationship with Provident and PSC. Non-public personal information is personally identifiable financial information that you provide to us; as a result of a transaction between you and Provident and PSC; or information that we otherwise obtain about you in connection with providing a financial product or service.

  * **We collect non-public personal information about you from a variety of sources, such as:**  
 
    * Information we receive from you on applications or forms received verbally, electronically, or in writing, including information such as Social Security numbers, addresses, e-mail addresses, income, assets, and debt;
    * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, including information we receive from a third party such as a credit bureau providing your credit history, credit score, or employment verification;
    * Information created as a result of your being a customer of PSC or your being a Provident member or nonmember joint owner on a deposit or loan account, such as account numbers, personal identification numbers (PIN), and passwords;
    * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others, including information about your transactions or experiences, such as insurance contracts issued to you, brokerage accounts, loan or deposit balance histories;
    * Information received from other sources to verify information that you provide on an application. This may be obtained from your current or past employers or other institutions where you have conducted financial transactions in the past.

  * **Parties who receive information from us--** The member information we collect is used to serve your accounts and meet your financial needs. Information may be used among the Provident affiliates, as well as with authorized third parties (see section 3 for further description), for a number of purposes, such as:  
 
    * To protect your accounts from unauthorized access or identity theft.
    * To process your requests such as loan applications, purchases, and ATM withdrawals.
    * To service your accounts by issuing checks, ATM cards, and account statements.
    * To keep you informed about financial services of interest to you.

  * **We share information with third parties when they are acting on our behalf, or acting jointly with us.** We may disclose the information we collect, as described above, with third parties that are acting on our behalf, including:  
 
    * Companies that perform support services for us, such as data processors, technical systems consultants and programmers, check printers, or companies that help us market Provident's products and services.
    * Financial institutions such as insurance companies or lenders that are acting in under joint programs with us, and provide financial services that are different than those we provide to you. If you prefer not to receive information about special offers from these companies, you may instruct us not to share member information for this purpose. Indicate your preference on the attached notification form and return it to us at any time.
    * There are other situations when we may disclose to third parties the member information we collect as permitted or required by law. In these cases, third parties could include credit bureaus, government entities, courts or other entities (in response to subpoenas and other legal processes), and those with whom you have requested us to share information.
  
  Please note: Provident does not share member information with other companies for the purpose of marketing their products to you, unless you specifically request in advance that we do so.

### Disclosure of Information About Former Members

If you decide to terminate your membership with Provident Credit Union or its affiliates, we will not share information we have collected about you, except as may be permitted or required by law.

### How We Protect and Use Member Information

We are committed to protecting the security and integrity of member information through procedures and technology designed for this purpose. For example:

  * We limit employee access to member information to those who have a business reason to know this information. Employees are required to honor our code of conduct, which includes standards to protect member confidentiality. They are subject to disciplinary action if they fail to do so.
  * We maintain policies and procedures covering the proper physical security of workplaces and records.
  * Our physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards meet or exceed federal standards regarding the protection of customer information.We require independent contractors and third parties who work with us to adhere to strict privacy standards through their contracts with use.
  * We use technological means (such as backup files, virus detection and eradication software, firewalls, and other computer software and hardware) to protect against unauthorized access or alterations to member data.

### What Members Can Do to Help

Provident Credit Union and its affiliates are committed to protecting the privacy of its members and customers. You can help by following these simple guidelines:

  * Protect your account numbers, card numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers) and passwords. Never keep your PIN with your check card or credit card which can provide free access to your accounts if your card is lost or stolen. 
  * Use caution when disclosing your account numbers, social security numbers, etc. to other persons. If someone calls you, explains the call is on behalf of the Credit Union, and asks for your account number, you should beware. Official credit union staff will have access to your information and will not need to ask for it.
  * Keep your information current. It is important that we have current information on how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent or unauthorized activity or use of an account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your address or phone number changes, please let us know.
  * Let us know if you have questions. Please do not hesitate to call us -- we are here to serve you!

### Your Right to Opt-Out

If you do not want us to give information about you to third parties, you can opt out at any time by contacting our Call Center at (650) 508-0300, or by completing the "Opt Out" form below and returning it in person to one of our community branch locations, or mailing it to us at the address provided on the form. It may take up to four weeks to implement your request.

Your preference will apply to all accounts linked to your Member Number. For joint accounts, any account holder can make their selection on behalf of the other joint account holders.

Privacy Form
